[
    {
        "question": "أَتَانَا",
        "answer": "came to us",
        "pcklId": "257",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "atānā",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " حَتَّىٰ أَتَانَا الْيَقِينُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُوتُوا",
        "answer": "were given",
        "pcklId": "527",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "ūtū",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "16",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَيَزْدَادَ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا إِيمَانًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُوتُوا",
        "answer": "were given",
        "pcklId": "528",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "ūtū",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "25",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَرْتَابَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَالْمُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُؤْتَىٰ",
        "answer": "he may be given",
        "pcklId": "529",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "yu'tā",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُؤْتَىٰ صُحُفًا مُنَشَّرَةً",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُؤْثَرُ",
        "answer": "imitated",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 14,
        "tlit": "yu'tharu",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ يُؤْثَرُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُؤْثَرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to transmit, to be related",
        "waznTlit": "yu'tharu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَإِحْدَى",
        "answer": "(is) surely one",
        "pcklId": "84",
        "rootWordId": 20,
        "tlit": "la-iḥ'dā",
        "frequency": "85",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا لَإِحْدَى الْكُبَرِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِحْدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "one",
        "waznTlit": "iḥ'dā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَأَخَّرَ",
        "answer": "stay behind",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "yata-akhara",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " لِمَنْ شَاءَ مِنْكُمْ أَنْ يَتَقَدَّمَ أَوْ يَتَأَخَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَأَخَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to delay, to stay behind",
        "waznTlit": "ta-akhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرَةَ",
        "answer": "the Hereafter",
        "pcklId": "150",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirata",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا بَلْ لَا يَخَافُونَ الْآخِرَةَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "235",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": "239",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذْ أَدْبَرَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "Then when",
        "pcklId": "342",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نُقِرَ فِي النَّاقُورِ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "343",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالصُّبْحِ إِذَا أَسْفَرَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "543",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ يُؤْثَرُ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "544",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا قَوْلُ الْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "545",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا أَصْحَابَ النَّارِ إِلَّا مَلَائِكَةً",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "546",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا عِدَّتَهُمْ إِلَّا فِتْنَةً لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "547",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "51",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "(is) but",
        "pcklId": "548",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "55",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ وَمَا هِيَ إِلَّا ذِكْرَىٰ لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "549",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَذْكُرُونَ إِلَّا أَنْ يَشَاءَ اللَّهُ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "650",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا أَصْحَابَ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Exceptive particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "for those who",
        "pcklId": "1394",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "lilladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "12",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا عِدَّتَهُمْ إِلَّا فِتْنَةً لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1395",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "15",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1396",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "19",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَيَزْدَادَ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا إِيمَانًا",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1397",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "24",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَرْتَابَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَالْمُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those",
        "pcklId": "1398",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "29",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِيَقُولَ الَّذِينَ فِي قُلُوبِهِمْ مَرَضٌ وَالْكَافِرُونَ مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2817",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "36",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِيَقُولَ الَّذِينَ فِي قُلُوبِهِمْ مَرَضٌ وَالْكَافِرُونَ مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2818",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "41",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ يُضِلُّ اللَّهُ مَنْ يَشَاءُ وَيَهْدِي مَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2819",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَذْكُرُونَ إِلَّا أَنْ يَشَاءَ اللَّهُ هُوَ أَهْلُ التَّقْوَىٰ وَأَهْلُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "آمَنُوا",
        "answer": "believe",
        "pcklId": "544",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "āmanū",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "20",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَيَزْدَادَ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا إِيمَانًا",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامَنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to believe",
        "waznTlit": "āmana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِيمَانًا",
        "answer": "(in) faith",
        "pcklId": "648",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "īmānan",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "21",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَزْدَادَ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا إِيمَانًا وَلَا يَرْتَابَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِيمَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "īmān",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْمُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "answer": "and the believers",
        "pcklId": "841",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "wal-mu'minūna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "27",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَرْتَابَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَالْمُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْلُ",
        "answer": "(is) worthy",
        "pcklId": "119",
        "rootWordId": 82,
        "tlit": "ahlu",
        "frequency": "127",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَذْكُرُونَ إِلَّا أَنْ يَشَاءَ اللَّهُ هُوَ أَهْلُ التَّقْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ه ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) People",
        "waznTlit": "hamza hā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَهْلُ",
        "answer": "and worthy",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 82,
        "tlit": "wa-ahlu",
        "frequency": "127",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَهْلُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ه ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) People",
        "waznTlit": "hamza hā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِآيَاتِنَا",
        "answer": "to Our Verses",
        "pcklId": "377",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "liāyātinā",
        "frequency": "382",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّهُ كَانَ لِآيَاتِنَا عَنِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَسَرَ",
        "answer": "and scowled",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 122,
        "tlit": "wabasara",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ عَبَسَ وَبَسَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ب س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَسَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to scowl, to frown",
        "waznTlit": "basara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَشَرِ",
        "answer": "(of) a human being",
        "pcklId": "84",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "l-bashari",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا قَوْلُ الْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "bashar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "answer": "the human (skin)",
        "pcklId": "85",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "lil'bashari",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوَّاحَةٌ لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "bashar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "answer": "to (the) human beings",
        "pcklId": "86",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "lil'bashari",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "57",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ وَمَا هِيَ إِلَّا ذِكْرَىٰ لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "bashar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "answer": "to (the) human being",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "lil'bashari",
        "frequency": "123",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَذِيرًا لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "bashar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُبْقِي",
        "answer": "it lets remain",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 150,
        "tlit": "tub'qī",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُبْقِي وَلَا تَذَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تُبْقِى",
        "waznEnglish": "to spare, to remain",
        "waznTlit": "tub'qī",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَنِينَ",
        "answer": "And children",
        "pcklId": "174",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "wabanīna",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَنِينَ شُهُودًا",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تِسْعَةَ",
        "answer": "(are) nine",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 183,
        "tlit": "tis'ʿata",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَيْهَا تِسْعَةَ عَشَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ت س ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تِسْعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "nine",
        "waznTlit": "tis'ʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَثِيَابَكَ",
        "answer": "And your clothing",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 211,
        "tlit": "wathiyābaka",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَثِيَابَكَ فَطَهِّرْ",
        "rootWord": "ث و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ثِيَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "been rewarded",
        "waznTlit": "thiyāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "the criminals",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "l-muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": "66",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَنِ الْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْتُ",
        "answer": "And I granted",
        "pcklId": "323",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿaltu",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْتُ لَهُ مَالًا مَمْدُودًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "We have made",
        "pcklId": "324",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "jaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا أَصْحَابَ النَّارِ إِلَّا مَلَائِكَةً",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "We have made",
        "pcklId": "325",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "jaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا عِدَّتَهُمْ إِلَّا فِتْنَةً لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جُنُودَ",
        "answer": "(the) hosts",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 265,
        "tlit": "junūda",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "49",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ن د",
        "waznEnglish": "with the forces",
        "waznTlit": "jīm nūn dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتٍ",
        "answer": "Gardens",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannātin",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حُمُرٌ",
        "answer": "donkeys",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 353,
        "tlit": "ḥumurun",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ حُمُرٌ مُسْتَنْفِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِمَار",
        "waznEnglish": "your donkey",
        "waznTlit": "ḥimār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْتُ",
        "answer": "I created",
        "pcklId": "164",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqtu",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْنِي وَمَنْ خَلَقْتُ وَحِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَخُوضُ",
        "answer": "indulge in vain talk",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 443,
        "tlit": "nakhūḍu",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنَّا نَخُوضُ مَعَ الْخَائِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ و ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاضُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to engage in idle talk, to converse vainly",
        "waznTlit": "khāḍu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخَائِضِينَ",
        "answer": "the vain talkers",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 443,
        "tlit": "l-khāiḍīna",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنَّا نَخُوضُ مَعَ الْخَائِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ و ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَآئِضِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they engage",
        "waznTlit": "khāiḍīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخَافُونَ",
        "answer": "they fear",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 444,
        "tlit": "yakhāfūna",
        "frequency": "124",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا بَلْ لَا يَخَافُونَ الْآخِرَةَ",
        "rootWord": "خ و ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَافَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fear, to be afraid",
        "waznTlit": "khāfa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "answer": "he turned back",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "adbara",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَدْبَرَ وَاسْتَكْبَرَ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn away, to depart",
        "waznTlit": "adbara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "answer": "it departs",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "adbara",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذْ أَدْبَرَ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn away, to depart",
        "waznTlit": "adbara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُدَّثِّرُ",
        "answer": "who covers himself",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 456,
        "tlit": "l-mudathiru",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَا أَيُّهَا الْمُدَّثِّرُ",
        "rootWord": "د ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د ث ر",
        "waznEnglish": "who covers himself",
        "waznTlit": "dāl thā rā",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْرَاكَ",
        "answer": "can make you know",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "adrāka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا سَقَرُ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": "101",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنَّا نُكَذِّبُ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذَكَرَهُ",
        "answer": "(may) pay heed to it",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhakarahu",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَنْ شَاءَ ذَكَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remember, to mention",
        "waznTlit": "dhakara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَذْكُرُونَ",
        "answer": "will pay heed",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "yadhkurūna",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَذْكُرُونَ إِلَّا أَنْ يَشَاءَ اللَّهُ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remember, to mention",
        "waznTlit": "dhakara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "a reminder",
        "pcklId": "191",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'rā",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "56",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ وَمَا هِيَ إِلَّا ذِكْرَىٰ لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "التَّذْكِرَةِ",
        "answer": "the Reminder",
        "pcklId": "281",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-tadhkirati",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا لَهُمْ عَنِ التَّذْكِرَةِ مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذْكِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "tadhkirat",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَذْكِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a Reminder",
        "pcklId": "282",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "tadhkiratun",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّهُ تَذْكِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذْكِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "tadhkirat",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَبَّكَ",
        "answer": "And your Lord",
        "pcklId": "916",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "warabbaka",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَرَبَّكَ فَكَبِّرْ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلِرَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "And for your Lord",
        "pcklId": "917",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "walirabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِرَبِّكَ فَاصْبِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "918",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "50",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالرُّجْزَ",
        "answer": "And uncleanliness",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 534,
        "tlit": "wal-ruj'za",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالرُّجْزَ فَاهْجُرْ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رُّجْز",
        "waznEnglish": "And uncleanliness",
        "waznTlit": "ruj'z",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَأُرْهِقُهُ",
        "answer": "Soon I will cover Him",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 596,
        "tlit": "sa-ur'hiquhu",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَأُرْهِقُهُ صَعُودًا",
        "rootWord": "ر ه ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُرْهِقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be hard on, to overburden, to cover",
        "waznTlit": "yur'hiqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَهِينَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) pledged",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 597,
        "tlit": "rahīnatun",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُّ نَفْسٍ بِمَا كَسَبَتْ رَهِينَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَهِينَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then pledge",
        "waznTlit": "rahīnat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرَادَ",
        "answer": "(does) intend",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 600,
        "tlit": "arāda",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "35",
        "arabicAyah": " مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا",
        "rootWord": "ر و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to intend, to desire, to want, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "arāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُرِيدُ",
        "answer": "Desires",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 600,
        "tlit": "yurīdu",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُؤْتَىٰ صُحُفًا مُنَشَّرَةً",
        "rootWord": "ر و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to intend, to desire, to want, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "arāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرْتَابَ",
        "answer": "may doubt",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 604,
        "tlit": "yartāba",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "23",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَرْتَابَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَالْمُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ي ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱرْتَابَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to doubt",
        "waznTlit": "ir'tāba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَزِيدَ",
        "answer": "I (should) add more",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 643,
        "tlit": "azīda",
        "frequency": "61",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ يَطْمَعُ أَنْ أَزِيدَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to increase",
        "waznTlit": "zāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَزْدَادَ",
        "answer": "and may increase",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 643,
        "tlit": "wayazdāda",
        "frequency": "61",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "18",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَيَزْدَادَ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا إِيمَانًا",
        "rootWord": "ز ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱزْدَادُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to increase",
        "waznTlit": "iz'dādu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "answer": "asking each other",
        "pcklId": "113",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "yatasāalūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتٍ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَسَآءَلُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to question, to ask, to inquire",
        "waznTlit": "yatasāalu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سِحْرٌ",
        "answer": "magic",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 666,
        "tlit": "siḥ'run",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ يُؤْثَرُ",
        "rootWord": "س ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِحْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they bewitched",
        "waznTlit": "siḥ'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَسْفَرَ",
        "answer": "it brightens",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 695,
        "tlit": "asfara",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالصُّبْحِ إِذَا أَسْفَرَ",
        "rootWord": "س ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسْفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to brighten",
        "waznTlit": "asfara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمِسْكِينَ",
        "answer": "the poor",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 708,
        "tlit": "l-mis'kīna",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَمْ نَكُ نُطْعِمُ الْمِسْكِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ك ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِسْكِين",
        "waznEnglish": "Dwell",
        "waznTlit": "mis'kīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَكَكُمْ",
        "answer": "led you",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 716,
        "tlit": "salakakum",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا سَلَكَكُمْ فِي سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ل ك",
        "waznEnglish": "to insert, to make enter",
        "waznTlit": "sīn lām kāf",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَفَاعَةُ",
        "answer": "intercession",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 782,
        "tlit": "shafāʿatu",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا تَنْفَعُهُمْ شَفَاعَةُ الشَّافِعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَفَٰعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "can intercede",
        "waznTlit": "shafāʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الشَّافِعِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the intercessors",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 782,
        "tlit": "l-shāfiʿīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا تَنْفَعُهُمْ شَفَاعَةُ الشَّافِعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَٰفِعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "can intercede",
        "waznTlit": "shāfiʿīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "شُهُودًا",
        "answer": "present",
        "pcklId": "156",
        "rootWordId": 801,
        "tlit": "shuhūdan",
        "frequency": "160",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَنِينَ شُهُودًا",
        "rootWord": "ش ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَاهِد",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) witnessing",
        "waznTlit": "shāhid",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَشَاءُ",
        "answer": "He wills",
        "pcklId": "218",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "yashāu",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "43",
        "arabicAyah": " مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا كَذَٰلِكَ يُضِلُّ اللَّهُ مَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَشَاءُ",
        "answer": "He wills",
        "pcklId": "219",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "yashāu",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "46",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَهْدِي مَنْ يَشَاءُ وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "wills",
        "pcklId": "220",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِمَنْ شَاءَ مِنْكُمْ أَنْ يَتَقَدَّمَ أَوْ يَتَأَخَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "wills",
        "pcklId": "221",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَنْ شَاءَ ذَكَرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَشَاءَ",
        "answer": "wills",
        "pcklId": "222",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "yashāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَذْكُرُونَ إِلَّا أَنْ يَشَاءَ اللَّهُ هُوَ أَهْلُ التَّقْوَىٰ وَأَهْلُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالصُّبْحِ",
        "answer": "And the morning",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "wal-ṣub'ḥi",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالصُّبْحِ إِذَا أَسْفَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُبْح",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "ṣub'ḥ",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاصْبِرْ",
        "answer": "be patient",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 818,
        "tlit": "fa-iṣ'bir",
        "frequency": "103",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِرَبِّكَ فَاصْبِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be patient",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابَ",
        "answer": "keepers",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥāba",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا أَصْحَابَ النَّارِ إِلَّا مَلَائِكَةً",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابَ",
        "answer": "(the) companions",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥāba",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا أَصْحَابَ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صُحُفًا",
        "answer": "pages",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 823,
        "tlit": "ṣuḥufan",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُؤْتَىٰ صُحُفًا مُنَشَّرَةً",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُحُف",
        "waznEnglish": "plates",
        "waznTlit": "ṣuḥuf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَعُودًا",
        "answer": "(with) a laborious punishment",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 840,
        "tlit": "ṣaʿūdan",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " سَأُرْهِقُهُ صَعُودًا",
        "rootWord": "ص ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَعُود",
        "waznEnglish": "ascends",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaʿūd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُصَلِّينَ",
        "answer": "those who prayed",
        "pcklId": "97",
        "rootWordId": 857,
        "tlit": "l-muṣalīna",
        "frequency": "99",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَمْ نَكُ مِنَ الْمُصَلِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصَلِّين",
        "waznEnglish": "praying",
        "waznTlit": "muṣallīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَأُصْلِيهِ",
        "answer": "Soon I will drive him",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 858,
        "tlit": "sa-uṣ'līhi",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَأُصْلِيهِ سَقَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُصْلِي",
        "waznEnglish": "to burn",
        "waznTlit": "uṣ'lī",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُضِلُّ",
        "answer": "does let go astray",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "yuḍillu",
        "frequency": "191",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "40",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ يُضِلُّ اللَّهُ مَنْ يَشَاءُ وَيَهْدِي مَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَضَلَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to let go astray, to mislead",
        "waznTlit": "aḍalla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُطْعِمُ",
        "answer": "feed",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 911,
        "tlit": "nuṭ'ʿimu",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَمْ نَكُ نُطْعِمُ الْمِسْكِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ط ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَطْعَمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to feed",
        "waznTlit": "aṭʿama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَطْمَعُ",
        "answer": "he desires",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 925,
        "tlit": "yaṭmaʿu",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ يَطْمَعُ أَنْ أَزِيدَ",
        "rootWord": "ط م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَطْمَعُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hope, to desire",
        "waznTlit": "yaṭmaʿu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَطَهِّرْ",
        "answer": "purify",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 928,
        "tlit": "faṭahhir",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَثِيَابَكَ فَطَهِّرْ",
        "rootWord": "ط ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَهَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to purify",
        "waznTlit": "ṭahhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَبَسَ",
        "answer": "he frowned",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 950,
        "tlit": "ʿabasa",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ عَبَسَ وَبَسَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَسَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to frown",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabasa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِدَّتَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their number",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 964,
        "tlit": "ʿiddatahum",
        "frequency": "57",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا عِدَّتَهُمْ إِلَّا فِتْنَةً لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا",
        "rootWord": "ع د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِدَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "you count",
        "waznTlit": "ʿiddat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "answer": "they (are) turning away",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 975,
        "tlit": "muʿ'riḍīna",
        "frequency": "79",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا لَهُمْ عَنِ التَّذْكِرَةِ مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّعْرِضُون",
        "waznEnglish": "He displayed them",
        "waznTlit": "muʿ'riḍūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَسِيرٌ",
        "answer": "difficult",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 986,
        "tlit": "ʿasīrun",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَٰلِكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ يَوْمٌ عَسِيرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَسِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you disagree",
        "waznTlit": "ʿasīr",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَشَرَ",
        "answer": "teen",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 990,
        "tlit": "ʿashara",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَيْهَا تِسْعَةَ عَشَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And live with them",
        "waznTlit": "ʿashar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "knows",
        "pcklId": "369",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamu",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "48",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَعْلَمُ جُنُودَ رَبِّكَ إِلَّا هُوَ وَمَا هِيَ إِلَّا ذِكْرَىٰ لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَنِيدًا",
        "answer": "stubborn",
        "pcklId": "200",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿanīdan",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّهُ كَانَ لِآيَاتِنَا عَنِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَنِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿanīd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "answer": "to forgive",
        "pcklId": "229",
        "rootWordId": 1071,
        "tlit": "l-maghfirati",
        "frequency": "234",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "11",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَذْكُرُونَ إِلَّا أَنْ يَشَاءَ اللَّهُ هُوَ أَهْلُ التَّقْوَىٰ وَأَهْلُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "غ ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّغْفِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "We will forgive",
        "waznTlit": "maghfirat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "غَيْرُ",
        "answer": "not",
        "pcklId": "147",
        "rootWordId": 1095,
        "tlit": "ghayru",
        "frequency": "154",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَى الْكَافِرِينَ غَيْرُ يَسِيرٍ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "so they will surely change",
        "waznTlit": "ghayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فِتْنَةً",
        "answer": "(as) a trial",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 1105,
        "tlit": "fit'natan",
        "frequency": "60",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "11",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا عِدَّتَهُمْ إِلَّا فِتْنَةً لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فِتْنَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(may) harm you",
        "waznTlit": "fit'nat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَرَّتْ",
        "answer": "Fleeing",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1118,
        "tlit": "farrat",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَّتْ مِنْ قَسْوَرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَرَّتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to flee",
        "waznTlit": "farrat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَّرَ",
        "answer": "thought",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1148,
        "tlit": "fakkara",
        "frequency": "18",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ فَكَّرَ وَقَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَكَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to think",
        "waznTlit": "fakkara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقُتِلَ",
        "answer": "So may he be destroyed",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 1176,
        "tlit": "faqutila",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ت ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَتَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to kill",
        "waznTlit": "qatala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُتِلَ",
        "answer": "may he be destroyed",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 1176,
        "tlit": "qutila",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ قُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ت ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَتَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to kill",
        "waznTlit": "qatala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَدَّرَ",
        "answer": "and plotted",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "waqaddara",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُ فَكَّرَ وَقَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to determine, to plot",
        "waznTlit": "qaddara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّرَ",
        "answer": "he plotted",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qaddara",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to determine, to plot",
        "waznTlit": "qaddara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّرَ",
        "answer": "he plotted",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qaddara",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ قُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to determine, to plot",
        "waznTlit": "qaddara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَقَدَّمَ",
        "answer": "proceed",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1183,
        "tlit": "yataqaddama",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لِمَنْ شَاءَ مِنْكُمْ أَنْ يَتَقَدَّمَ أَوْ يَتَأَخَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَقَدَّمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to precede, to proceed",
        "waznTlit": "taqaddama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَسْوَرَةٍ",
        "answer": "a lion",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1197,
        "tlit": "qaswaratin",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَرَّتْ مِنْ قَسْوَرَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق س ر",
        "waznEnglish": "a lion",
        "waznTlit": "qāf sīn rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُلُوبِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their hearts",
        "pcklId": "154",
        "rootWordId": 1222,
        "tlit": "qulūbihim",
        "frequency": "168",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "31",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِيَقُولَ الَّذِينَ فِي قُلُوبِهِمْ مَرَضٌ وَالْكَافِرُونَ مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلْب",
        "waznEnglish": "you will be returned",
        "waznTlit": "qalb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْقَمَرِ",
        "answer": "By the moon",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1229,
        "tlit": "wal-qamari",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا وَالْقَمَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ق م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق م ر",
        "waznEnglish": "the moon",
        "waznTlit": "qāf mīm rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَالَ",
        "answer": "Then he said",
        "pcklId": "1593",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "faqāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَالَ إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا سِحْرٌ يُؤْثَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلِيَقُولَ",
        "answer": "and that may say",
        "pcklId": "1594",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waliyaqūla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "28",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِيَقُولَ الَّذِينَ فِي قُلُوبِهِمْ مَرَضٌ وَالْكَافِرُونَ مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They will say",
        "pcklId": "1595",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَمْ نَكُ مِنَ الْمُصَلِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْلُ",
        "answer": "(the) word",
        "pcklId": "1713",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qawlu",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هَٰذَا إِلَّا قَوْلُ الْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْل",
        "waznEnglish": "say",
        "waznTlit": "qawl",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُمْ",
        "answer": "Stand up",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qum",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " قُمْ فَأَنْذِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَامَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to stand up, to rise, to establish",
        "waznTlit": "qāma",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَبِّرْ",
        "answer": "magnify",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "fakabbir",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَرَبَّكَ فَكَبِّرْ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَبِّرْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to magnify",
        "waznTlit": "kabbir",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاسْتَكْبَرَ",
        "answer": "and was proud",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "wa-is'takbara",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَدْبَرَ وَاسْتَكْبَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَكْبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be arrogant",
        "waznTlit": "is'takbara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكُبَرِ",
        "answer": "(of) the greatest",
        "pcklId": "95",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "l-kubari",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا لَإِحْدَى الْكُبَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُبْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kub'rā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكِتَابَ",
        "answer": "the Scripture",
        "pcklId": "298",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "l-kitāba",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "17",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَيَزْدَادَ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا إِيمَانًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكِتَابَ",
        "answer": "the Scripture",
        "pcklId": "299",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "l-kitāba",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "26",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَرْتَابَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ وَالْمُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَسْتَكْثِرُ",
        "answer": "(to) acquire more",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1259,
        "tlit": "tastakthiru",
        "frequency": "167",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَمْنُنْ تَسْتَكْثِرُ",
        "rootWord": "ك ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَكْثَرْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to multiply, to acquire more",
        "waznTlit": "is'takthar",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُكَذِّبُ",
        "answer": "deny",
        "pcklId": "170",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "nukadhibu",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنَّا نُكَذِّبُ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَسَبَتْ",
        "answer": "it has earned",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 1269,
        "tlit": "kasabat",
        "frequency": "67",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُّ نَفْسٍ بِمَا كَسَبَتْ رَهِينَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَسَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to earn",
        "waznTlit": "kasaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَفَرُوا",
        "answer": "disbelieve ",
        "pcklId": "282",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "kafarū",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "13",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا عِدَّتَهُمْ إِلَّا فِتْنَةً لِلَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to disbelieve",
        "waznTlit": "kafara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَافِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the disbelievers ",
        "pcklId": "509",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "l-kāfirīna",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَى الْكَافِرِينَ غَيْرُ يَسِيرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَٰفِرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "disbelieve[d]",
        "waznTlit": "kāfirūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْكَافِرُونَ",
        "answer": "and the disbelievers",
        "pcklId": "510",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "wal-kāfirūna",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "33",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِيَقُولَ الَّذِينَ فِي قُلُوبِهِمْ مَرَضٌ وَالْكَافِرُونَ مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَٰفِرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "disbelieve[d]",
        "waznTlit": "kāfirūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُّ",
        "answer": "Every",
        "pcklId": "350",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kullu",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُّ نَفْسٍ بِمَا كَسَبَتْ رَهِينَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "351",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kullu",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُؤْتَىٰ صُحُفًا مُنَشَّرَةً",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "has been",
        "pcklId": "1320",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِنَّهُ كَانَ لِآيَاتِنَا عَنِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَكُ",
        "answer": "we were",
        "pcklId": "1321",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "naku",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَمْ نَكُ مِنَ الْمُصَلِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَكُ",
        "answer": "we used to",
        "pcklId": "1322",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "naku",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَمْ نَكُ نُطْعِمُ الْمِسْكِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُنَّا",
        "answer": "And we used to",
        "pcklId": "1323",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنَّا نَخُوضُ مَعَ الْخَائِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُنَّا",
        "answer": "And we used to",
        "pcklId": "1324",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنَّا نُكَذِّبُ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْفَ",
        "answer": "how",
        "pcklId": "72",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "kayfa",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْفَ",
        "answer": "how",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "kayfa",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ قُتِلَ كَيْفَ قَدَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَوَّاحَةٌ",
        "answer": "Scorching",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1357,
        "tlit": "lawwāḥatun",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لَوَّاحَةٌ لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ل و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَوَّاحَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Scorching",
        "waznTlit": "lawwāḥat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاللَّيْلِ",
        "answer": "And the night",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "wa-al-layli",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذْ أَدْبَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَثَلًا",
        "answer": "example",
        "pcklId": "89",
        "rootWordId": 1369,
        "tlit": "mathalan",
        "frequency": "169",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "38",
        "arabicAyah": " مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا",
        "rootWord": "م ث ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَثَل",
        "waznEnglish": "then he assumed for her the likeness",
        "waznTlit": "mathal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَمْدُودًا",
        "answer": "extensive",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1379,
        "tlit": "mamdūdan",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْتُ لَهُ مَالًا مَمْدُودًا",
        "rootWord": "م د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّمْدُود",
        "waznEnglish": "and prolongs them",
        "waznTlit": "mamdūd",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "امْرِئٍ",
        "answer": "person",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1381,
        "tlit": "im'ri-in",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُؤْتَىٰ صُحُفًا مُنَشَّرَةً",
        "rootWord": "م ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱمْرِئ",
        "waznEnglish": "an evil man",
        "waznTlit": "im'ri",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَرَضٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a disease",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1386,
        "tlit": "maraḍun",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "32",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِيَقُولَ الَّذِينَ فِي قُلُوبِهِمْ مَرَضٌ وَالْكَافِرُونَ مَاذَا أَرَادَ اللَّهُ بِهَٰذَا مَثَلًا",
        "rootWord": "م ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّرَض",
        "waznEnglish": "I am ill",
        "waznTlit": "maraḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَلَائِكَةً",
        "answer": "Angels",
        "pcklId": "145",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "malāikatan",
        "frequency": "206",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا أَصْحَابَ النَّارِ إِلَّا مَلَائِكَةً",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَمْنُنْ",
        "answer": "confer favor",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1419,
        "tlit": "tamnun",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَمْنُنْ تَسْتَكْثِرُ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَنَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to favor",
        "waznTlit": "manna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَمَهَّدْتُ",
        "answer": "And I spread",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1421,
        "tlit": "wamahhadttu",
        "frequency": "16",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَهَّدْتُ لَهُ تَمْهِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "م ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَهَّد",
        "waznEnglish": "to spread",
        "waznTlit": "mahhad",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَمْهِيدًا",
        "answer": "ease",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1421,
        "tlit": "tamhīdan",
        "frequency": "16",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَهَّدْتُ لَهُ تَمْهِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "م ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَمْهِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "they are preparing",
        "waznTlit": "tamhīd",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَالًا",
        "answer": "wealth",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 1427,
        "tlit": "mālan",
        "frequency": "86",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْتُ لَهُ مَالًا مَمْدُودًا",
        "rootWord": "م و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] wealth",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَنْذِرْ",
        "answer": "and warn",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "fa-andhir",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قُمْ فَأَنْذِرْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنذَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to warn",
        "waznTlit": "andhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَذِيرًا",
        "answer": "A warning",
        "pcklId": "109",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "nadhīran",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " نَذِيرًا لِلْبَشَرِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنَشَّرَةً",
        "answer": "spread out",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1471,
        "tlit": "munasharatan",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ كُلُّ امْرِئٍ مِنْهُمْ أَنْ يُؤْتَىٰ صُحُفًا مُنَشَّرَةً",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّنَشَّرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Will spread",
        "waznTlit": "munasharat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَظَرَ",
        "answer": "he looked",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "naẓara",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ نَظَرَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَنْفِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "frightened",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1499,
        "tlit": "mus'tanfiratun",
        "frequency": "18",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُمْ حُمُرٌ مُسْتَنْفِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَنفِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and advance",
        "waznTlit": "mus'tanfirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَفْسٍ",
        "answer": "soul",
        "pcklId": "285",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "nafsin",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُّ نَفْسٍ بِمَا كَسَبَتْ رَهِينَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْفَعُهُمْ",
        "answer": "will benefit them",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1502,
        "tlit": "tanfaʿuhum",
        "frequency": "50",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا تَنْفَعُهُمْ شَفَاعَةُ الشَّافِعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to profit, to benifit",
        "waznTlit": "nafaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُقِرَ",
        "answer": "is blown",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1508,
        "tlit": "nuqira",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نُقِرَ فِي النَّاقُورِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ق ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُقِرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to blow",
        "waznTlit": "nuqira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّاقُورِ",
        "answer": "the trumpet",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1508,
        "tlit": "l-nāqūri",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا نُقِرَ فِي النَّاقُورِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ق ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّاقُور",
        "waznEnglish": "is blown",
        "waznTlit": "nāqūr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّارِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Fire",
        "pcklId": "135",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "l-nāri",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا جَعَلْنَا أَصْحَابَ النَّارِ إِلَّا مَلَائِكَةً",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاهْجُرْ",
        "answer": "avoid",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1542,
        "tlit": "fa-uh'jur",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالرُّجْزَ فَاهْجُرْ",
        "rootWord": "ه ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱهْجُرْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avoid",
        "waznTlit": "uh'jur",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَهْدِي",
        "answer": "and guides",
        "pcklId": "138",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "wayahdī",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "44",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ يُضِلُّ اللَّهُ مَنْ يَشَاءُ وَيَهْدِي مَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحِيدًا",
        "answer": "alone",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 1593,
        "tlit": "waḥīdan",
        "frequency": "68",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْنِي وَمَنْ خَلَقْتُ وَحِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "و ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَحِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) one (kind)",
        "waznTlit": "waḥīd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذَرْنِي",
        "answer": "Leave Me",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 1600,
        "tlit": "dharnī",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْنِي وَمَنْ خَلَقْتُ وَحِيدًا",
        "rootWord": "و ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ذ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave, to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "wāw dhāl rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَذَرُ",
        "answer": "it leaves",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 1600,
        "tlit": "tadharu",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُبْقِي وَلَا تَذَرُ",
        "rootWord": "و ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ذ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave, to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "wāw dhāl rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "التَّقْوَىٰ",
        "answer": "to be feared",
        "pcklId": "198",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "l-taqwā",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَذْكُرُونَ إِلَّا أَنْ يَشَاءَ اللَّهُ هُوَ أَهْلُ التَّقْوَىٰ وَأَهْلُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَقْوَى",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "taqwā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسِيرٍ",
        "answer": "easy",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yasīrin",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَى الْكَافِرِينَ غَيْرُ يَسِيرٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسِير",
        "waznEnglish": "We (have) made it easy",
        "waznTlit": "yasīr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ",
        "answer": "that may be certain",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1660,
        "tlit": "liyastayqina",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "14",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَسْتَيْقِنَ الَّذِينَ أُوتُوا الْكِتَابَ",
        "rootWord": "ي ق ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَيْقَنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be convinced, to be certain",
        "waznTlit": "is'tayqanat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَقِينُ",
        "answer": "the certainty",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1660,
        "tlit": "l-yaqīnu",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " حَتَّىٰ أَتَانَا الْيَقِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ي ق ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "firmly believe",
        "waznTlit": "yaqīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَمِينِ",
        "answer": "(of) the right",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "l-yamīni",
        "frequency": "71",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا أَصْحَابَ الْيَمِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) a Day",
        "pcklId": "302",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmun",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَٰلِكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ يَوْمٌ عَسِيرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِيَوْمِ",
        "answer": "(the) Day",
        "pcklId": "303",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "biyawmi",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "74",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُنَّا نُكَذِّبُ بِيَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    }
]